TANVEER MAHENDRA

User Experience Designer

mtanveersingh.github.io mtanveersingh@gmail.com +(49) 170 4414140 Konstanz, Germany (DE)

SUMMARY

I have been designing product experiences & interfaces for more than 3 years. With my background in technology, I like to get my hands on code from time to time. For me, the design is not a concept specific to only the end product but is also a process that cuts across each stage of the user experience lifecycle. Being a LEGO® enthusiast, I gravitate naturally towards rapid prototyping.

SKILLS

Research: Remote design sprint and brainstorming using Miro • Data analysis • Personas & user journey • Cognitive walkthrough • A/B testing

Prototyping: Rapid prototyping using Invision or Adobe XD • Hands-on experience with HTML, CSS and Javascript

Design: Strategy & visual presentation

- Cross-platform experiences User flows
- Wireframes & mock-ups using Sketch,
 Figma & Adobe suite Motion design using
 Principle & After Effects Style guides & developer hand-off using Zeplin

EDUCATION

University of Konstanz

M.Sc. in Computer & Information Science Konstanz, Germany | Oct 2017 - Present

• Specialization in Human-Computer Interaction.

Pune University

B.Eng. in Information Technology Pune, India | Jul 2011 - May 2015

• Experience designer of the PICT IEEE Student Branch and IEEE INDICON 2014.

EXPERIENCE

User Experience Design Intern

Formigas GmbH | Konstanz, DE

Jan 2020 - Present

- Redesigning the brand identity of Formigas' revolutionary lottery app, CleverLotto.
- Analyzed user context from real-world and designed a new intuitive playing interaction for the web users.

Research Assistant

University of Konstanz | Konstanz, DE

Jul 2018 - Dec 2019

- Performed quantitative analysis of the usability evaluation study data for self-directed training of patient transfer movements.
- Developed a crowd simulation experiment in virtual reality for a behavioral research study related to one's perception of human body sizes.
- Implemented a study experiment in virtual reality for analyzing human's perception of various information visualization methods.

UX Design Consultant

Freelance | Pune, IN

Jun 2016 - Jun 2017

- Conducted design sprints and usability testing for Tweeny technologies Pvt. Ltd. across their multiple projects.
- Designed a cross-platform design system for Shoreline, an IoT-based startup.

Creative Technologist

TouchMagix Media Pvt. Ltd. | Pune, IN

Jun 2015 - Jun 2016

- TouchMagix is a manufacturer of gesture based interactive platforms for brand engagement, entertainment and education.
- I took the responsibility from strategy to design of MagixBox, a plug&play gesture based interactive system for walls and floors.
- Reduced the physical footprint of the product by 30% leading to a significant reduction in the packaging and transportation costs.

Research & Development Intern

TouchMagix Media Pvt. Ltd. | Pune, IN

Jul 2014 - Apr 2015

 Developed a clothing pattern recognition prototype by training cascading classifiers using HAAR based model. The pattern recognition provided a 5% more accuracy than the pretrained models.